Diwali Puja, The Importance Of Meditation
Los Angeles, (USA) – 3 November 2002
光明节崇拜 冥想的重要性
2002年11月3日 美国洛杉矶
I wish you all a very happy Diwali
我祝你们有个非常快乐的光明节
To see all of you here
见到你们所有人到来
is itself such a joy for me
对我而言 这本身就是极大的喜悦
that you all have taken to
Sahaja Yoga in such a beautiful way
见到你们以如此美丽的方式接受霎哈嘉瑜伽
It's your own ,Self is your own
霎哈嘉瑜伽是属于你们自己的
真我是你们自己的
Spirit is your own
灵是你们自己的
but to take to Self is difficult
但要达至这个真我却不容易
It's only your desires,I think which is being fulfilled
我认为 （要达至真我）仅需要你们的愿望
且这个愿望正在实现中
And that's how you have
got your self-realisation
而那也是你们得到自觉的方式
It cannot be forced , as you know very well
自觉不能强加于人 你们都很了解这一点
It has to work out only with your
desire only, with your surrendering
它只能通过你的愿望 通过你的交托来实现
No use talking about it
谈论它是无用的
No use convincing about it
说服别人相信它也是无用的
What works out is
your desire simple as that
能够成就的只有你的愿望 就是那么简单
The power of desire within you works it out
你内在愿望的力量会将它成就
There are many who are not here
得到自觉的人非常多 他们现在不在这儿
who have got their realization
all over the world
他们遍布世界各地
I remember all of them
我记得他们所有人
and all of you should remember them
你们所有人也应当记住他们
Today is a nice day, when we can think
今天是美好的一天 我们可以想起
of all those who are enlightened in this world
世界上所有那些已得到觉醒的人
That's the real Diwali
那是真正的光明节
the enlightenment of human beings
It'snot candle,it's not some lamp
点亮人类的不是蜡烛 也不是灯
but it's human beings, If they are enlightened
then there's no problem any more left
而是人类 若他们得到觉醒 便不会有任何问题
The problems come with the
people who are not enlightened
所有问题都来自那些未觉醒的人
because they are in the darkness
They are groping in the darkness
因为他们在黑暗之中 他们在黑暗中摸索
and some of them are don't know also that
他们有些人还未意识到
they are completely ignorant of realities
自己对实相完全一无所知
Once you come to Sahaja Yoga
and enlighten yourself
一旦你们来到霎哈嘉瑜伽 让自己得到启迪
you see in that light in that light
what's is good and what is bad, to begin with
首先你们会在光之中看到孰对孰错
And then you grow into it beautifully
然后你成长成熟 成为这光 非常美妙
just like these flowers who are all the
time happy, all the time giving you joy
正如这些花朵总是洋溢着快乐 给你喜乐
In the same way when you are
enlightened with that light
同样 若你被点亮 有了那光
you don't seek anything
你不会向外追寻什么
you got everything within you
你从内在得到所有一切
Keep the lights on
你要尽力保持好这光
The another thing you can do is
你们可以做的另一件事是
with your light you can enlighten other people
用你的光你们可以点亮他人
Like we have done here
正如这儿我们所做的
we had enlightened one candle
我们点燃一支蜡烛
with that we have enlightened all of them
借此我们点燃了所有蜡烛
So you all can do it
因此你们都可以做到
because you have got that light within you
因为在你们内在已得到那光
With that light you can enlighten others
用那光你们可以点亮他人
and they can feel their joy of their Spirit
他们将感受到自身灵的喜乐
It's something to be seen now
现在你们看见这些事情正在发生
like so many lights you have put
就像你们打开了这么多的灯
in the same way,you are the lights
for the whole world
同样的 你们是整个世界的光
It's not sufficient that you have
got the light
仅仅你们得到光那还不够
but also you have to give light to others
你们还必须把光给予他人
you have to enlighten others
just like these candles
你们必须点亮他人 如同点燃这些蜡烛一般
Once you start doing that
一旦你们开始那样做
you'll realise what you have got
你便会意识到你获得了什么
and then you'll respect yourself
然后你会尊重自己
and you'll behave in a (matter) manner
that behoves a saint, could be a sage
你的行为举止理应如圣人 亦或如智者一般
without proclaiming anything
但无需向他人宣告什么
Inside your being
you just develop that beautiful
从内在你发展出那种美好的
extremely beautiful temperament
that is joy-giving
能够给予喜乐的 极其美好的气质
You don't want to give any
false ideas about yourself
你不愿发表任何关于自身的谬见
because whatever is the trut is with you
因为凡是真理都在你之内
There's no need to tell something
untruth about yourself
没有必要去讲述关于自身的虚假谬论
People will realise that you are realised souls
人们将认识到 你是个自觉的灵
they will just feel your subtle nature
your reality
他们将感受到你精微的本质 你的实相
whether you come from India or you
come from England, or from America
无论你来自印度 英国还是美国
You all have that ocean of love
and knowledge within you
你们内在都拥有这爱与知识的海洋
Be sure that it's all there
你们要相信全都在那
only you first enjoy your own ocean of love
只有你首先享受自身爱的海洋
First you enjoy that
首先你会享受它
and then you can enjoy in others also
然后你才能享受他人内在的海洋
I don't have to tell you
我不必告诉你
that you love each other or anything
你们要相亲相爱之类的话
You just love
你们只是相亲相爱着
you just understand
你们就是明白
you just spread your light among yourself
你们只是在彼此之间传播着光
Sometimes you get frustrated
with other people in your country
有时你会为你们的国家
maybe in your city maybe in your village
或你们的城市或你们村庄里
that the people who are not
yet enlightened
尚未觉醒的那些人而感到气馁
But best thing is to work it out.
但最好就是让他们得到自觉
You have to work it out
你们必须将这个任务完成
You know, I had first one lady
你们知道 我这边第一个得到自觉的是位女士
very old lady one
一位非常年老的女士
who got her realisation from me
最先从我这得到自觉
And there, you are all here
然后 现在你们都在这
In the same way, you all can also
do the job of realisation
同样你们也能够做 给人自觉的工作
For that you don't need any calculations
做这工作 你们不用任何的计算
you don't need any thanksgiving
也不需任何的感恩
It's just there, and it works out
它就在那 它自会成就
What do you do for a light
为了获得光 你们做了什么
Just see, you just put near the candle
看 你只是靠近蜡烛
and you get the light
然后你便得到了光
In the same way it is
Your enlightenment is such
同样的道理 你们的觉醒也同样如此
that it will give light to thousands
and thousands of people all over the world
它能点亮全世界成千上万的人
As you know
正如你们所知道的那样
there are many countries who
we have to still approach
需要我们着手去工作的国家还有许多
but we will do that
但我们会去做
just locate and find out where
do you have to go
只要锁定你们要去的地方
and where you have to work
找出你们需要工作的地方
Firstly, you are capable of
giving realisation, you are
首先 你们有能力给人自觉 你们能
Have confidence that you can
give realisation to people
一定要相信你们能给人自觉
for which you don't need any help
而且你们可以无需任何帮助
single person can do it ,thousands can do it
单个人可以做到 成千上万的人也可以做到
It's very important for the Diwali
of the whole world
这对整个世界的光明节是非常重要的
that we should give realisation to
people, Very important
我们要给人自觉 这非常的重要
Now, in Sahaja Yoga
现在 在霎哈嘉瑜伽
many people are such who are
little frustrated with themselves
许多人都因自身而感到有些气馁
Specially with their past
对于他们的过去尤为如此
Forget the past. Past is not important
忘记过去 过去并不重要
what is important is present
重要的是当下
At this present moment what have
you to do
当下此刻 你要做什么
You don't have to worry about the past
你不必担心过去
that I've done this ,I've done that
我做过这个 我做过那个
What's done is finished
所有做过的已经结束了
now you look out for the future
现在你要着眼将来
what can you do for the future
你能为将来做些什么
And somehow or other with the
light, you see your path
你用某种方法藉由那光 看到自己的道路
you get rid of all this darkness
and you know how far to go
你去除所有的黑暗 你知道要走多远
how to meet people and how
to spread Sahaja Yoga
怎样找到人们,怎样传播霎哈嘉瑜伽
It's something you have already within you
这都是你内在早已存在的
but you have to first of all
establish your connection with it
但你首先必须建立与这部分的连接
If you have established you connection
with that ocean that you have
若你们与你们内在的海洋建立好连接
you can definitely work it out
你们就一定能成功
work it out in such a beautiful manner
且以一种非常美好的方式获得成功
and you'll be amazed
how you'll be successful
这种成功的方式将令你们惊叹
The success that you get out of
all this ignorance
你们成功地摆脱所有这些无明
you are amazed at it
but you have the light
你们会为之赞叹 但你们确实拥有光
With the light you do remove all the darkness
藉由光 你们清除了所有的黑暗
don't have to think about it, just removes
不必去思虑 就能清除黑暗
because you have it
因为你们已拥有光
But if you don't have the light
但若你们没有光
then, no use talking about it,no use doing it
那么空口谈论是无用的 无论做什么也是无用的
because it doesn't give any success
因为不会有任何成就
On the contrary, it's a failure
failure of the worst type
相反 它会失败 以最糟糕的方式失败
And can be very dangerous for people
对人而言会非常的危险
We have had very funny experiences
also in the Sahaja Yoga
在霎哈嘉瑜伽我们 曾有过非常可笑的经验
But I think they all are running one by one
但是我想 他们都忙于追逐一个又一个（教条）
that 'this should not have been done,
that was wrong.'
这个不应该做 那个是错的
Now what blinds you we should find out
现在我们应该发现这样做是多么的盲目
In this country it's such a
money-oriented country,America is
在这个国家 一个如此金钱导向的国家 美国
which has spread all over the world
这种金钱导向已传播到整个世界
And being money-oriented
you do get enamoured
在这种导向中 你们确实受到迷惑
you do feel that you must
make money out of Sahaja Yoga
你们切实感到你们 要用霎哈嘉瑜伽赚钱
There are some who do not think like
that but they are still running after making money
有些人不那样想 但他们仍在追逐金钱
There is no need at all for you to make money
你们所有人都没必要追逐金钱
or to find for yourself a kind of
a security in money
没必要为你自己求得一种金钱保障
Your security is in-built within you
你们的保障是在你们之内先天就设置好的
So all these outside things which
are absolutely unnecessary
因此所有这些完全不必要的身外之事
should not blind you
不应令你们变得盲目
Now, if you have the light you can see clearly
现在若你们有光 你们便可以明辨
And this help of the Divine
这些上天的帮助
you see that very clearly in your life
你们可以在你生活中非常清晰地看到
And you are surprised how the Divine
has helped you at different points
你们会惊讶 上天如何在不同领域给你们帮助
I get letters from people who say
Mother,thank you very much
我收到一些人的来信说 "母亲 非常感谢你"
I got rid of my problem
I got rid of my enemies
我解决了我的问题 我除掉了我的敌人
all kinds of thing. But I've done nothing
各种各样的事 但是我什么都没有做
It's your light which has removed the darkness
是你的光清除了这些黑暗
If you are ignorant
如果你们是无明的
then only the light can remove
the darkness ofyour ignorance, also
那么也只有光能够清除 你们无明的黑暗
Actually, we don't know how much
there is the power of the light
事实上我们并不知道 这光的力量有多强大
As you can see here
正如你们在这可以看到
every light is giving such a lot of
每束光都给予如此多
not only energy but also complete picture
不仅有能量还有完整的画面
so thus you can make out
因此你们才能理解
For example, you can make out if
somebody is a realised soul or not
比如 你们可以辨别某人是否自觉的灵
It's not necessary that you have
to go near that person
并不需要靠近那人
or take any special care or anything
或特别在意那人或其他什么
You will just know that this
person is a realised soul or not
你们就是会知道 此人是否一个自觉的灵
I've had many such experience
我有许多的亲身经历
where I found that people don't know
who is a realised soul
发现人们并不知道 谁是自觉的灵
very surprising
非常令人惊讶
If you know who is a realised soul
如果你们知道谁是自觉的灵
then half of your problem is over
那么一半的问题都会解决
Now the second one is the problem
of how to convince that fellow
现在第二点是如何让那人相信
what he is capable of doing
他能够做些什么
I find that problem also with Sahaja yogis
我发现霎哈嘉瑜伽士也同样存在这个问题
They are capable of very great work
all over the world
他们能在世界各地做出非常伟大的工作
They can find out so many things which
normally normal people cannot find out
他们能发现许多平常人无法发现的事
But Sahaja yogis can immediately find out
但霎哈嘉瑜伽士可以立刻发现
what sort of a person they are facing
他们面对的是何种类型的人
This is the difference
这便是区别所在
that means you know the truth
那意味着你了解真实的事
Truth about everyone
关于每个人的真相
truth about the whole situation
关于整体大局的真相
truth about who is just boasting
关于谁在自吹自擂
or just making up a story
或在编造谎言
or some sort of a hypocrisy
或某种虚伪的真相
It's not difficult because now
you have the sight
这并不难 因为现在你们有这种眼力
you can see with your light
用你们的光你们能够看到
what's wrong or what's good with others
何人不妥 何人妥当
Such a blessing it is for you
这样的祝福赐予你
that you cannot be cheated
令你们不受任何欺骗
because also you are looked after by the Divine
也因为你们是由上天看护的
guided all the time by the Divine
时刻受着上天的指引
Have faith in the Divine
have faith in the Divine
一定要对上天有信心 对神有信心
thats very important
那是非常重要的
As you have faith in a candle
就如你们相信蜡烛那样
have faith that the Divine will give
you light will guide your path
相信神会赐予你光 会指引你的道路
will take you to the right place
to do the right things
会带你去到正确的地方 做正确的事
I mean so many have seen
我是说 有许多人都曾经历过
the experiences I've with you
我与你们同在的体验
I did not tell you how much
people have written to me
我没告诉过你们有多少人都给我写信
how they found things working out
说他们如何发现事情在成就
Despite all that we are collective
除此之外 我们是一个整体
we are nice to each other , we don't tell lies
我们善待彼此 我们不说谎话
we don't try to destroy anyone
我们不伤害任何人
That means we are much above
all human failings
那意味着我们大大超越了人类所有的缺陷
and this is only because of the light
这只是因为那光
You can see where you are faltering
你们能看到自己在何处摇摆退缩
It's just you see for yourself
你看清楚这些只是为了你自己
For that, I think meditation is
the most important thing as such
为此 我想冥想是最重要的事
Every day you should do meditation
你们每天都应当冥想
Those who do not do meditation
are capable of falling down
那些不冥想的人会跌落下去
because meditation is like putting oil
into the lamp
因为冥想就像给油灯添油
Those who do not meditate think they
那些不冥想的 且认为自己
can do without it are sadly mistaken
应不需要冥想的人 是错误可悲的
They have to meditate morning and evening
他们必须早晚冥想
The problem is everything comes
so handily, so simple
问题是每件事都如此触手可得 如此轻易简单
that they don't understand
that meditation is very important
以致他们并不明白冥想是非常重要的
Typical. Not you but there are many I know
尤其是 不是你们 而是有很多我知道
who get realisation, who don't meditate
已得到自觉的人 他们并不冥想
And their style is different
他们风格迥异
Their nature is different
他们的个性与众不同
Meditation is such a soothing thing
冥想是如此能够给人慰藉的事
such a beautiful way of connection
with the Divine
与上天如此美妙的连接
that all your problems
而所有你们的问题都会
get solved in that meditative mood
在冥想的状态中得到解决
If you are not meditating, you
are not following meditation
若你们不去冥想 你们不用冥想这种方式
then maybe your light will go down
那你们的光可能会暗淡下去
It won't give sufficient light
它将无法给你们充足的光
It's important, very important
这是很重要的 非常重要
to find out about yourself,
about others in the meditation
在冥想中去发现你自己 发现别人
How to do meditation many people ask
很多人问 如何冥想
Don't do anything
什么都不用做
to just go into thoughtless awareness
只是进入到无思虑的觉醒状态
Try to go to the thoughtless awareness
试着进入无思虑的觉醒状态
If you can get into that condition
of thoughtless awareness
若你们能进入无思虑的境界
you've done your job
你们便完成了你们的工作
because that's the point
where you are with the truth
因为那是你们与真理
with the reality, with the joy
与实相 与喜乐
with everything that is so fundamental
与根本的每样事物同在的境界
When you meditate try not to make
some sort of a function out of it, no
冥想时 不要企图从中产生某种功能 不要
Meditation is somethin silencing
yourself silencing your thoughts
冥想是让你自己宁静下来 让你的思维宁静下来
and going to that deep ocean which
is within you itself
进入你内在的深海之中
But supposing you don't do that
假如你不那样做
if you don't meditate I can make
out immediately
如果你不冥想 我可以立刻认出
those who are meditating and
those who are not
谁有冥想而谁没有
It's not difficult for me
那对我一点也不费力
Those who do not meditate
are always hesitating
那些不冥想的总是摇摆不定
They are confused, They can't understand
他们很迷惑 他们不能理解
And that's why meditation
那便是为何冥想
is the most important thing in Sahaja Yoga
是霎哈嘉瑜伽中头等重要的事
Just like a light burns with the
electricity flowing in it
正如灯能发光是因电流的流动
you can see or buy because
of the candles
你们能够看见是因为蜡烛的燃烧
in the same way meditation is a
同样的 冥想是一种
continuous availability of the Divine Force
能够持续运用上天力量的方式
That will reduce all your aspirations
它会减少你们所有的欲望
Not only that but takes out all
the negative thoughts
不但如此还会带走所有负面的想法
It takes out all the discouraging things
它能带走所有消极的事物
And when you are meditating like that
thoughtless awareness
若你能那样冥想在无思虑的觉醒状态
then you'll be amazed how you are
helped from within and without
那么你将惊讶 你如何从内在和外在获得帮助
It's a terrible power that works
它是种巨大的力量在运作着
this thoughtless awareness
即这种无思虑的觉醒状态
So those who do not meditate
所以那些不冥想的人
cannot go very much far with
the advantage of Sahaja Yoga
不会因着霎哈嘉瑜伽的好处而走得更远
One should try to meditate
我们应尝试去冥想
and go up to the point of
thoughtless awareness
上升至无思虑觉醒的境界
So what happens to you
那么什么会发生在你身上
If you are in thoughtless awareness
如果你在无思虑的觉醒中
what happens to you is that
you get the confidence
会发生的是 你得到信心
complete confidence of divinity
得到对神完全的信心
You know you have that
你知道你自己拥有那信心
I've seen children coming from our
school in Dharamsala
我见过来自霎哈嘉学校的孩子
extremely confident,and extremely humble
极其自信 也极其谦卑
And I asked them:"What do you do?"
我问他们:"你们是怎样做的?"
They said:Mother, we meditate
他们说:“母亲 我们会冥想”
We meditate in the school in the evening
我们傍晚在学校冥想
and that meditation helps
冥想对我们帮助很大
Imagine these small children can say that
想想这些小孩子说的话
so why not you also understand it
为何你们不能明白这点
that meditation will give you security
冥想会带给你们安全感
It will give you
它会给予你们
real enlightenment and a complete
connection with the Divine
真正的启迪以及与神完全的连接
Without the connection of the Divine
若没有与上天的连接
what's the use of doing Sahaja Yoga
练习霎哈嘉瑜伽又有何用处
I know the people who are meditating
我知道人们谁有冥想
who have gone down into their being
and who are very developed
谁进入到他们内在的存有 谁发展良好
Also I know people who are little superficial
而且我也知道谁是肤浅的人
Your depth is in thoughtless awareness
你的深度便是体现在无思虑的觉醒中
Is a very important point which you should reach
这是你们应该达致的一个非常重要的阶段
Looking at anything
看着任何事物
if you are thoughtlessly aware
若你们是无思虑的意识状态
then you really become reflective about it
那么你们真的会成为它的反映
Just works out that way
就是那样来成就
I don't knowhow far you can remain
in that condition
我不知道 你们能保持在那个状态中多久
But even for a second you can achieve it
但即使你能达到它只有一秒钟
you start achieving it more and more
你便会开始越来越多地达到
I've talked so much about meditation before
关于冥想我之前说过很多
but today when I see all these candles burning
但今天当我看到这么多点燃着的蜡烛
I think they are all meditative
我想它们都在冥想中
They are all in meditation
它们都在冥想状态
and that's how they're burning
它们就是那样在点燃着
In the same way
同样的道理
Sahaja yogis who meditate, I know
我知道哪些霎哈嘉瑜伽士有冥想
And those who don't, I know
而那些没有冥想的 我也知道
And if they have problems, I know
why the problems are there
若他们有问题 我也知道问题的原因所在
Main thing is your connectio with the Divine
is only possible , when you meditate
重点是你与上天的连接那 只有当你冥想时
and become thoughtlessly aware
进入无思虑的状态才能实现
That's the point where Divine works
那是上天力量在这个点起作用
it helps you , It comes to your help in such way
在这个点它会帮助你
上天就是以这样的方式帮助你的
that you don't know
how you have achieved it
你都不知道自己是怎样成功的
So thoughtless awareness is the first
point all of you should achieve
所以,无思虑的状态是你们首先应该达到的
Very important
这非常的重要
After that we can achieve something else
那之后 我们可以达到其他阶段
but the first step is thoughtless awareness
但是第一步是无思虑的觉醒
It's very important to
become thoughtlessly aware
达到无思虑的觉醒非常重要
because then there are no thoughts
coming from the left or right
因为随后便不会再有来自左右脉
from the (past) or the future
来自过去和将来的思维
Just in the present you are there
It's something you all have
你就在当下 这是你们所有人都拥有的（状态）
It's not that I'm saying that to you
这并非因为我是这么跟你们说的
but all of you have this
而这的确是你们所有人都拥有的
but steady yourself
但要稳定你们自己
You have to steady yourself
你必须将自己稳定
at thoughtless awareness
在无思虑的觉醒状态
How long - that's not the point
能有多久,那不重要
The point is once you've touched it
重点是 一旦你达到它
you'll go on touching it
你就将持续达到它
Many people meditate but their
thought process is going on
许多人冥想 但他们的思想却忙个不停
They are not thoughtlessly silent
他们还不在无思虑的状态
Now this is the one point
which is very important
现在这是非常重要的一点
If you have to grow
若你要成长
you should be absolutely in connection
with the Divine,through thoughtless awareness
你绝对应在无思虑状态中与上天连接
You don't have to pray , you
don't have to call anyone
你不必祈祷,你不必呼唤任何人
nothing , it just works because it is within you
什么都不用,它就是那么有效 因为它就在你之内
All these thoughts are bombarding
from both two sides in your mind
所有这些思想都从你大脑的左右两边不停地轰炸你
These thoughts that are coming
那些出现在你头脑中的思维
to you have no meaning with you
对你没有任何意义
They do not substantiate you yourself
它们不会支持你
you are an ocean
你自己就是一个海洋
And you have to get into that
state of thoughtless awareness
你必须进入那无思虑的觉醒状态
It is always described in all the great books
这种状态在一切伟大的著作中通常都有所描述
but not so clearly as I am telling you
但却没有我告诉你们的这样清楚
I don't say
我不是说那些
that some of you do not get thoughtless
awareness so they are good for nothing
未达到无思虑状态的人一无是处
- no
不是那样
But please try. You can all get into
that state of thoughtless awareness
但请尝试一番 你们全都可以进入无思虑的觉醒
even for a second ,if you get it
即便是一秒 若你们这样想
it's a very good idea
那是个不错的主意
Then you go on increasing that second
然后你可以继续延长那一秒
I think is a reflecting mind
我想这是一种反映式的大脑
When you look at something ,you
do become thoughtlessly aware
当你看到什么 你便变得无思虑
and then your mind reflects to
the depth of what you see
然后你的大脑反映出你所见到的深度
That's how you all will become
那便是你们所有人真正成为
really very creative Sahaja yogis
极富创造力的霎哈嘉瑜伽士的方式
What I find that this state of thoughtless
awareness is not established by many
我发现 并没有太多人建立了无思虑的觉醒状态
which is not good
这并不好
Today, on this day of Diwali I would say
今天在光明节这个日子 我要说
that you enlighten yourself with
thoughtless awareness
你们要通过无思虑的觉醒来开悟你们自己
It is not difficult, it's within you
这并不难 它就在你们内在
because thoughts are coming
from this side and that side
因为思虑是来自这边和那边
And they are not the waves of your brain, no
它们不是你的脑波 不是
just your own reactions
只是你自己的反应
But in case you meditate in the
real sense of the word
但如果你在真正意义上去冥想
then you'll get into that thoughtless awareness
那么你会进入无思虑觉醒
which is a very important point
这是非常重要的
And all these nonsensical thoughts
所有这些无聊的思想
which are of no use to you will disappear
对你毫无用处的思想 都将消失
They won't be there and then
your growth is possible
它们从那消失 然后你才可能成长起来
and you'll grow very well
你会成长得非常好
Many people are here who will say
很多在这的人会说
'Mother, we don't get that state'
"母亲 我们没有达到那个状态"
Try. Try that
试试看 试试看
I don't believe you cannot get it
我不相信你们不能达到
All of you can get that thought
that 'I can get it'
你们所有人都可以有这个心念"我能达到"
And you will get it
然后你便达到
In that, you don't have to
discard anything
在此过程中 你不必放弃任何事
you don't have to see anything
你不必去看任何东西
just go into meditation
只是入静
and you'll be amazed how it will work out
你将惊讶它会怎样成就出来
Of course, you are very much there
当然 你们非常多的人已经在那个境界中
most of you but still, I would say
你们大多数的人 但我仍要说
increase that thoughtless awareness that area
增长那无思虑的觉醒状态 扩展那个领域
Today is very important because
of this day of Diwali
今天非常重要因为今天是光明节
Diwali is supposed to be Enlightenment Day
光明节被认为是觉醒之日
But enlightenment within is
但这个觉醒却是指内在的觉醒
how much you are in
thoughtless awareness
你达致无思虑觉醒状态的程度
And everything works out
每件事都会成就出来
because you are the ocean of it.
因为你就是无思虑觉醒状态的海洋
You have it within yourself
你在内在拥有它
Only, you have to tap it
唯一的一件事是 你必须去发掘它
If you don't tap it then
it doesn't work out
若你去不发掘 那么它便成就不出来
You have to just tap it
and you'll be amazed
你们一定要去发掘它 然后你们会惊讶
that you are a source of such joy
你们是如此喜乐的源头
source of such happiness
如此快乐的源头
I should say source of real enlightenment
我要说 (你们)是真正开悟的源头
So today's message is that
所以今天的主旨是
while meditating
go into thoughtless awareness
冥想时 要进入无思虑的觉醒状态
No thought is important
because it's your own creation
无思虑是重要的 因为思维是你们自己所创造的
But if you have to become (one)
with the divine creation
但若你们要与上天的创造合一
you have to get to that state of thoughtless
awareness,minimum of minimum
最低限度 你们必须达致无思虑的觉醒
What's that comes to you
gradually if you grow
若你们真的成长 这个状态将会逐渐到来
and you'll be amazed
而且 你们会惊叹
how you'll be able to grow
into Sahaja Yoga in a very big way
在一条极其宽广的道路上你们
将会怎样得到成长进入霎哈嘉瑜伽
Thank you very much!
非常感谢你们!